We have learned about the hash function in the previous video, a function that converts a given big
phone number to a small, practical integer value is called a hash function.
The mapped integer value is used as an index in hash table.
In simple terms, a hash function marks a given or a big number or string to a small empty showed that
can be used as index in the hash table.
A good the hash function should have following properties that efficiently computable and should uniformly
distribute the keys.
Each table position equally likely for each key.
Consider this example, we have that data of arbitrary length school message.
This is the hash function that blender that we have talking about it and it will produce a fixed length,
the length, the hash, it's called digest.
And this is that number is used to be stored in the hash table.
So the hash table and array that stores pointers to records corresponding to a given phone number and
entry in hash table is nil.
If no existing phone number has hash function, equal value equal to the index of that entry.
So this is Daniel.
This the hash table.
It's an array of LinkedIn lists, so we we can imagine that the hash table is as an as a this is array
one two zero one two three four five and and so on and on.
Index number zero, we have a linkage list that contains elements.
OK.
This is the hash table.
We will see it in there and in depth in the next videos, how it works and how the animation works in
that a hash table.
And we will implement it in see language and in.
So there is a collision.
Collision handling.
If we are producing the same hashes for different, for different like for year that we have seen in
the like, a music file could be the same hash as a text file.
So there is a collision.
End date address.
So there is a coalition handling and hash tape, since a hash function gets a US a small number for
a big key.
There is possibility that two keys result in the same value.
That situation, where a newly inserted team maps to an already occupied slot in hash table is called
collision.
If we are putting data here and the same hash will result in the same index for, for example, if I
have a music file here and here is a text that that we have seen in the previous video.
Text produced the same hash and then the music produced the same hash.
I need to put it here.
So.
In this situation, there is a collision and must be handled using some collision handling technique.
What are these techniques?
We have two techniques like training.
This is this example will give us an air changing solution for handling a collision.
So the idea is to make each cell of hash table point to a linked list of records that have same hash
function.
Value chaining is simple, but requires additional memory outside that tape.
Up been everything as the second solution for handling the collision.
Up in addressing is an open addressing, all elements are stored in the hash table itself.
Each table entry contains either a red card or nil when searching for an element.
We examined the tables slots one by one until the desired element is found, or it is clear that the
element is not in the table.
In the next videos, we will see the how to collect the gold, to handle the collision and how the hash
table was.